So tell me. How was Hawaii?
夏威夷好玩嗎？
- It was unbelievable. - Oh, yeah?
-太讚了 -是嗎？
- Well, what happened? - I met this guy.
-有艷遇啦？ -我遇到一個男人
It was the best week of my life.
那是我此生最美的一周
It was just a little vacation romance.
一段浪漫的假期
But he was so sweet.
他好溫柔
He took me to all these cool local places.
他帶我到好多好玩的地方
We went scuba diving...
我們去潛水...
- Snorkeling. - Mountain climbing.
-浮潛 -爬山
We went cliff diving.
懸崖跳水
Well, we got a little drunk.
我們喝醉了
- He gave me... - A back rub.
-他幫我... -擦背
We slow danced...
我們深情擁舞...
- in the rain.
在雨中
But it wasn't just about the sex.
這不只是性而已
He pounded me like a mallard duck.
我倆沒有別的關係 我們倆的關係只是性的關係
It ended kind of weird, though.
不過結束的有點怪
When I asked for his number, he said he's...
我跟他要電話，他卻說他...
- Married. - Gay.
-結婚了 -是同志
- Entering the priesthood. - He doesn't believe in phones.
-正要投身宗教事業 -他不喜歡用電話
He just kind of ran away.
他就這樣走了
You know, it was just a little fling, but...
這只是段露水姻緣...
I won't forget my week...
但我永遠忘不了他...
- with Henry Roth.
羅亨利
- Henry Roth. - Harry.
-羅亨利 -小利利
Harry Paratesticles.
硬漢亨利
- Henry Roth.
-羅亨利
Henry Roth, why didn't you tell me you were a secret agent?
亨利，為何不早說你是密探？
I prefer intelligence operative, and I couldn't tell you until I knew you.
「情報員」比較好聽 我不能隨便跟你透露
Well, can I call you when I land?
我回去能打電話給你嗎？
You can call me, but I' II be in Peru. I said that a little loud.
行，但到時我已經在秘魯了 我太大聲了
Come on, that's a 187, code blue. We got the wolf sleeping at night.
總部，狀況 野狼騎走，整夜狂飆
He's slipping his arm in the drawer and out comes the cookie jar. All clear.
他從山林來越過原野 跨過小溪向前行，完畢
Got it?
明白？
Well, maybe when you get back from Peru.
也許等你從秘魯回來再打
- I don't think that's an option, Lisa. - Linda.
-我想那是不可能的，莉莎 -是琳達
I know. I changed your name for your protection.
我知道，我這是為了保護你
We have to go our separate ways now.
我們得分手了
Well, goodbye.
再見了
Got it! Moving out!
收到，馬上來
- What the hell is your problem? - Just keep going, I' II give you $20.
-你搞什麼啊？ -繼續騎，我給你二十塊錢
- You got it. How's your balls? - Killing me. Hit it.
-沒問題，你的蛋沒破吧？ -我痛斃了，全速前進
Easy, Honah Lee.
輕一點，大法師
Hey, I' m a person, not a seal
我是人，不是海豹
Well, I am a vet, not a doctor. So just hold still, or I won't give you a treat.
我是獸醫，我專醫動物 別亂動，再動就不幫你醫了
I know, it's okay. You see that, kids?
痛吧，孩子們看好了
You see what happens when you play with sharks?
跟鯊魚玩就會有這種下場
Now, why you gotta spread those lies? Sharks are like dogs.
你別散播謠言 鯊魚跟小狗一樣
They only bite when you touch their private parts.
亂碰他小弟弟，他就會咬你
That's a good title for my documentary.
我的紀錄片可以用這標題
Sharks: They Only Bite When You Touch Their Private Parts.
鯊魚，碰他小弟就咬死你
Or you could call it, Sharks: They Tried to Eat My Kidney.
不然就用 「愛吃腰子的鯊魚」
All right, enough already. You too, Willie.
別笑了，你也一樣，小威
All of you.
你們全都一樣
He just cast a spell on us.
他對我們下咒
All right. Put this on four times a day for two weeks.
一天換藥四次，持續兩周
- You can handle that. - What's wrong with that turtle?
-你自己可以換 -那只海龜怎麼了？
Lung problems because he smoked too much turtle weed...
他的肺生病了 因為他抽太多大麻了...
...which is bad for you. Right, Ula?
你也一樣別抽了
What? I don't smoke weed.
幹嘛？我又不抽大麻
Hey, Honah Lee? How's that hot wahine nympho from Ohio?
大情聖，那個下港來的花癡妹呢？
Great. I dropped her off at the airport this morning.
我今早在機場跟她分手了
Come on, I need some details.
拜託，說清楚一點
You get some booby, some assy, a pull on your poi-poi? Come on.
你摸過、爽過了？
Daddy, what's a nympho?
阿爸，花癡是什麼？
Oh. The nympho is the state bird of Ohio.
花癡是花枝的一種
You're the state idiot of Hawaii.
你還是大烏賊咧
Here you go. Bite the fish, chew the fish, love the fish. Enjoy.
沒錯，小威 要大口吃魚也要愛魚
- You crack me up, kamaaina. - Oh, yeah?
-你真愛搞笑，大情聖 -是嗎？
- One of these days... - Yeah?
-總有一天... -幹嘛？
...you'll show one of those tourists such a good time...
你會讓來渡假的美女難以忘懷...
...she'll wanna stay on the island.
她就會想留在這島上
Why do you say mean things like that...
你幹嘛說這麼恐怖的話？
...and why is your foot on my pillow?
還把你的髒腳踏在我枕頭上
I don't want your ass on it, either. Get up! Get up!
屁股也不行，起來！
It could happen.
這很有可能
Then you won't be able to go on your boat trip to Alaska.
然後你就不能駕船去阿拉斯加了
You'll be stuck here, waking up next to the same old, ugly broad, just like Ula.
你會被卡在這裡 跟我一樣娶個老母豬
- Just kidding, guys. - About the old part or the ugly part?
-開玩笑的啦 -你是說老還是母豬的部份？
Henry, come quickly! It's Jocko!
醫生，快來，肥仔病了！
Jocko! What's going on with you, buddy?
肥仔，你怎麼了？
Don't be scared. Everything's gonna be fine.
別怕，不會有事的
Just stay calm. All right.
冷靜點
Willie, I don't need you to see this. Get out of here, now!
小威，別看，快出去！
Okay, check the temperature of the pool Go! Hurry!
檢查一下池子的溫度，快去！
What are you doing? I meant check the thermometer!
你耍寶啊？去看溫度計！
Give me a hand. Let's go!
幫我忙，快點！
Get me two fish from the barrel Now.
幫我拿兩條魚過來
- Okay. - Just hang in there.
-好 -忍著點
- Here. - It 's gonna be all right.
-來了 -不會有事的
That's a little warm. Go to the bottom of the barrel, please.
太溫了，拿桶底的魚
Okay, there. That's good. Thank you.
很好，謝謝
Come on, buddy, take it. Take it.
來啊，吃下去
- He's not responding! - I know, Alexa!
-他沒反應 -我知道啦
Sorry, I smacked you. You needed the fish-slap to calm down.
抱歉打了你 你要跟死魚一樣冷靜，懂嗎？
- Do you understand? Are you calm? - Yes. Fish-slap calm me.
-你夠冷靜嗎？ -夠，死魚打醒了我
I'm gonna try to get him breathing manually...
我要動手讓他深呼吸...
...so I need your face next to his mouth to see if it's working.
你把臉貼在他嘴旁注意動靜
- Are you ready? - Yes.
-準備好了？ -好了
- One, two, three! - Nothing, nothing!
-一、二、三 -沒動靜！
All right! Try it again. If it doesn't work we'll perform a tracheotomy.
好，再試一次 要是再沒用，就動手術
We don't wanna do that, so let's pray this works. One more time.
我們可不想那樣，再來一次吧
One, two...
一、二...
That's a lot of vomit.
吐的真多呢
This is why I got into this business.
這就是我進這行的理由
To save sea animals.
要拯救海洋動物
You should go wash yourself off, okay?
你去洗個澡吧？
Maybe try some turpentine. That might take the stink away.
用薑汁洗，可以去腥味
Yeah, high-five is right, buddy.
幹的好啊，兄弟
I knew you were gonna burp, but the vomit thing was awesome!
我知道你會打嗝，但吐就太猛了
That's what she gets for eating my roast beef sandwich.
這是她偷吃我三明治的下場
Willie, did you see that?
小威，你看到了吧？
Captain's log: November 5th, 6:45 a.m.
船長日誌，11月5日 清晨6點45分
I've taken the Sea Serpent for a trip around the island of Oahu.
我駕著海蛇號到歐胡島
It is by far the longest voyage she has yet underaken...
這是它航行最遠的一次...
...and its completion will signal that she's ready...
此次出航成功代表它已經...
...for our great journey to Bristol Bay...
準備好航向布里斯托灣...
...whose unspoiled walus habitat will yield an abundance of...
野生海象的棲息地 那裡有數不清的...
Damn it!
哇咧！
Are you kidding me?
不會吧？
Aloha, honey. What can I get for you?
你好，帥哥，要點什麼？
I guess I' II take a cup of coffee.
我想我就來杯咖啡吧
- You guess? - Yeah, I already ate breakfast.
-你想？ -我吃過早餐了
I need to kill some time before the Coast Guard gets here to tow my boat.
我只是在等人救援，幫忙拖船
What did you eat?
你早餐吃了什麼？
I had a Reese's Peanut Butter Cup and some Gatorade.
花生巧克力加寶礦力
They're not breakfast. I get you Spam and eggs.
那不算早餐，來客火腿蛋吧
Nick, I need Spam and eggs.
大胖，來客火腿蛋
Hey.
嗨
- You like the peanut butter cups? - Yes.
-你喜歡花生巧克力？ -對
Want me to put peanut butter cups in your eggs?
我幫你在蛋裡加一點吧？
No, that's okay.
不用了
Peanut butter cups.
花生巧克力
- Hey, Sue, nice haircut. - Mahalo, Lucy.
-阿蘇，你髮型好美 -謝謝你，露西
Are you staring at me or her?
你在看我還是看她？
Because you're starting to freak me out.
老子我被你搞毛了了哦
Settle down and eat your pancakes.
別激動，吃你的早餐吧
I think she's a local girl I wanted to go up to her...
我想她是在地人 我想去跟她搭訕...
...but I was kind of off my game. But, man, was she cute, though.
但我不敢 不過，她超可愛的
I thought you liked your bitches from out of state.
我以為你喜歡外國妞
Yeah, that's usually my policy. Make sure I don't get tied down.
對，我一向如此 免得被人綁住
Freeze that image right there.
別動
There's the little fella. Congratulations, Mommy.
小傢伙在這 恭喜你，媽咪
Sounds to me like someone is afraid of commitment.
看來有人怕承諾
Let me guess.
我猜猜看
Your high school sweetheart got drunk at party...
你高中的馬子去轟趴...
...then cheated on you with whole wrestling team.
結果喝醉跟同學大搞性派對
Close. Actually, it was my college girlfriend Tracy.
差不多了，不過是大學的馬子
And it wasn't a wrestling team. It was her academic advisor.
也不是跟同學搞，是跟老師搞
- Oh, she liked the older man. - Older women. About 50 years older.
-她喜歡老男人 -是老女人，大她50歲
I hope you shot the stupid tramp.
你有海扁那隻老母狗吧？
What's with the "tramp" and the "bitches" talk?
怎麼說話這麼粗？
- Are you drunk or something? - I apologize for nasty talk.
-你喝醉了？ -對不起
I am grouchy due to lack of recent physical intimacy.
最近沒啥搞頭，我有點抓狂
Shut up, because here comes one-time-only opportunity.
閉嘴，千載難逢的機會來了
What I will do now is go into your office and become naked.
我要進你辦公室，脫個精光
Next move is up to you.
接下來就看你的了
I may not be as limber as I once was...
我也許沒以前那麼柔軟了...
...but I make up for it with enthusiasm and willingness to experiment.
但我會用熱情和技巧來彌補你
I don't know if you realize, I'm not into guys.
你不明白，我不喜歡男人
Hey, Mr. Peanut Butter Cups.
花生巧克力男
Hey, Mr. Could -Kill -Me-in-One-Punch. How you doing?
你好，猛男大廚師
- You're back. - Couldn't get enough of that Spam.
-你回來了 -就是忘不掉那些火腿
Fry some up and throw some eggs on it.
幫我煎一點，再加個蛋吧
- You got it. - All right, mahalo.
-沒問題 -真多謝啦
- Hi, Lucy. - Hi, Nick.
-你好，露西 -你好，大胖
You know, why don't you try this?
你何不試試這招？
It's kind of a hinge.
這就像門柱一樣
- Now, why didn't I think of that? - Well, you're too close to the project.
-我怎麼沒想到？ -當局者迷、旁觀者清
Don't be hard on yourself.
別自責了
Right. Sometimes you need an outsider's perspective.
是啊，旁觀者有時看的更清楚
Fresh eye never hurts.
多問個人準沒錯
I'm Lucy.
我是露西
Yes. I' m Henry Roth.
我是羅亨利，幸會
- Nice to meet you.
-幸會
It's pretty. Keep up the good work.
做的很不錯，繼續加油
Wait. I see you're sitting there alone. Do you wanna come and sit down?
等等，你好像一個人來 要不要過來一起坐？
- Sure, that'd be great, if that's all right. - Okay.
-好啊，挺不錯的 -很好
- So are you an architect? - I am not. I' m in fish.
-你是建築師？ -不是，我工作跟魚有關
Oh, that's where the smell is coming from.
難怪會有那股味道
Yeah, yeah, I was feeding a walrus this morning...
是啊，我早上餵了海象...
...and I thought I got most of it off of me, but guess I didn't.
我以為我都洗乾淨了 但是大概並沒有吧
- I love that smell. - No, you don't.
-我喜歡這味道 -不會吧
- Fish don't even like that smell. - No, I do. My dad's a fisherman.
-連魚都不喜歡這種味道了 -真的，我爸是漁夫
He and my brother Doug, they go out to sea for months at a time.
他跟我弟道格都一起出海
And I miss them so much while they're gone that when they come back...
每次回來，因為我太想他們...
...I just hold on to them for five minutes each.
我都會抱他們整整五分鐘
And they smell just like your hands. It's the best smell in the world.
他們身上的味道就像你的手 世上最香的味道
Well, my fingers are available...
有需要的話...
...for your sniffing pleasure anytime you need them.
隨時歡迎你聞
- Wanna? - Okay.
-想聞嗎？ -想
Sea lions are known for their athleticism...
海獅以好動聞名...
...and dolphins are known for their intelligence.
海豚則以智慧聞名
- Walruses are known for their... - Tusks?
-海象的聞名之處... -是象牙？
Their tusks. Also their male parts can get pretty gigantic.
象牙，還有超壯觀的大雞雞
Yeah, yeah, it's the second biggest out of all the mammals.
沒錯，那是世上第二大的
- What's the first? - I think Tattoo-Face.
-第一大的是誰？ -那個大花臉吧
Ilike your laugh.
我喜歡你的笑聲
Ilike you making me laugh.
我喜歡你逗我笑
I hate to break this up, but we're setting up for lunch.
抱歉打擾，要供應午餐了
Oh, okay. Sorry, Sue.
歹勢，阿蘇
And the real cool thing about walruses is they're very mysterious.
海象最酷的地方，就是很神秘
- Mysterious? - Yeah, yeah.
-神秘？ -對
We don't really know what they're like in the wild.
我們不知他們的野外生活
Don't they just sleep on icebergs and yawn all the time?
他們不是愛睡冰山、打哈欠嗎？
All we really see is what they do outside of the water...
那是離開水面，我們所看到的...
...but who knows what they do under the ice...
他們在冰下的生活就神秘了...
...where they spend two-thirds of their lives.
他們有2/3的時間是在水裡
Well, maybe they're intimidating the other creatures with their big winkies.
也許他們在下面 用大雞雞威脅別人
That is one theory.
那是其中一個理論
- I have to go. - Where you going?
-我得走了 -你要上哪？
It's my dad's birthday, and we go every year and we pick a pineapple.
今天我爸生日 我們每年都會去摘鳳梨
- It 's a tradition. - That sounds nice. Okay, well...
-這是傳統 -聽來不賴，好吧...
...I had a great time.
我今天很愉快
- Me too. - Okay.
-我也是 -好
Would you like to have breakfast again tomorrow morning, same time?
你想再來吃早餐嗎？ 明天早上，同一時間？
- Because I teach an art class at 10. - Really?
-因為我早上十點要上美術課 -真的？
- Yeah. - I wish I could make it...
-真的 -希望我趕得來...
...but, yes, I will be there.
好，我會來
- Take care. - Okay.
-保重 -好
- One for the road. It is fishy. - Got you good.
-再回味一下，哇，超腥的 -吸的真大口
- Aloha. - Aloha!
-再見！
See you tomorrow.
明天見
Oh, my God.
我的老天
Oh, my goodness.
我的媽呀
Shit.
靠
I had a bee on me.
有蜜蜂叮我
- All right. - He was a big one.
-是哦 -很大一隻呢
Which means "look at those two shitheads."
這話是說 「看這兩個呆子」
That was the stupidest-looking swing I' ve ever seen.
這是我看過最鳥的揮桿了
I'm gonna take a Molokai on that one.
我來讓它更像鳥
No throwing. Come on.
不能用丟的，拜託
Stop laughing, you hyenas. Let's see what you get.
別笑，死孩子，你們打給我看
Okay, you heard me. Go! Go!
聽見沒，快去！
Show papa what you got.
表現給老爸看看
- You suck, you're good at everything. - Father of the Year strikes again.
-爛小孩，只會起肖 -你真是模範父親啊
By the way, cuz, I met this sexy, blond tax attorney at Starbucks today.
對了，老大 我今天在星巴克遇見金髮律師
I told her you the kahuna she wanna have fun on this island.
我跟她說想找樂子就要來找你
You want her number?
你要不要她的電話？
You pimping tourists for me again?
你又幫我拉客了？
Yes! I live vicariously through you, remember?
對，我靠你維繫我的生命
My life sucks.
我的人生太慘了
Now, come on. Give her the Waikikiki sneaky between the cheeky.
跟她來個巨猩喬揚大戰金髮妹
Ula needs it. I imagine I did it and then I can get through another weekend.
我需要嘛，我會想像是我上場 這樣我才活的下去
I'm staying in. Sorry. Thank you, though.
我哪都不去，謝了
- What? - Hey, Dad!
-什麼？ -阿爸！
Not now, Keanu Mokokokakau.
別吵啦，賠錢貨
But your stitches are bleeding.
可是你傷口在流血耶
It must've been my huge back-swing.
一定是我打到的
You think you can stitch me up after I get back from surfing?
今晚在我衝浪後幫我縫好，好嗎？
- Yeah, looking forward to it. - I wouldn't surf with a wound like that.
-好，再幫你繡朵花 -流著血去衝浪...
You might attract a shark.
會引來鯊魚
What's wrong with that? Sharks are naturally peaceful
少唬爛了，鯊魚天性溫和
Is that right? How'd you get that nasty cut, anyway?
是嗎？那你的傷哪來的？
A shark bit me.
鯊魚咬的
Nice.
好耶
Go smoke another one, bro.
再多去嗑點藥吧
That shark theory's starting to catch on.
你的鯊魚理論已經開始流行了
Now, will everybody keep it down...
大家安靜...
...while I whack the crap out of this thing?
等我把球打過去
Sit! Stay! Shit! No!
停，靠！
Where the hell is it?
跑哪去了？
Looking for something?
找東西啊？
Oh, my God! What are you doing here?
老天，你在這幹嘛？
The same thing you are. Looking for my ball.
跟你一樣，找球啊
This is weird. I' ve been thinking about you all morning, all day.
怪了，我想了你一整天
Can't wait to have breakfast with you again.
我等不及明早跟你共進早餐了
I know. And I just wanna eat you up.
我知道，我也想把你吃了
- Really? - Yeah. Tomorrow and the next day...
-真的？ -對，明天、後天...
...and the next day and the next day. - All right. Okay.
-大後天，大大後天 -好了、好了
Oh, my.
哇咧
Oh, Lucy, that feels so good.
露西，好舒服哦
No, my nipples are too sensitive. Stop that.
不行，我乳頭很敏感，別這樣
- What happened? - Your ball hooked into that cart...
-怎麼回事？ -球打中車...
...bounced back and hit you in the head. It was freaking hilarious.
彈回來正中你的頭 真是超爆笑的
- What? - Who's Lucy?
-什麼？ -露西是誰？
And what's up with your nipples?
你的乳頭又怎麼了？
I can't be falling for a local I ain't ever going back to that diner.
我不能愛上在地人 我不會回那間小吃店的
- This where you got hit? - Yes!
-你被打中這裡？ -對
You're so lucky you're a professional cliff diver in Hawaii.
還好你是夏威夷的專業跳崖手
- Yeah, well, it's a living. - I' m a tax attorney.
-我很專業 -我是稅務律師
- We never get to have any fun. - Is that right?
-超無聊的職業 -是嗎？
I'd like to do something extra fun tonight.
我今晚想找點樂子
Taking it deep, aren't you?
你真是又急又渴啊
How about another fishbowl for the lady?
阿丁，再給小姐來杯大藍鳥
- Why don't I just tap a keg for her? - Okay.
-乾脆開一桶酒給她喝吧？ -好啊
I think I' m getting kind of drunk.
我好像有點醉了
- Are you getting drunk? - Getting there.
-你咧？ -快了
So, what are you thinking?
你在想什麼？
What am I thinking?
我在想什麼？
Actually, I' m not drunk at all, Noreen, and neither are you...
其實我根本沒醉 你也一樣...
...because there's no alcohol in these drinks.
因為飲料裡根本沒酒精
Sadly, I' ve used this technique many times.
抱歉，這伎倆我用過很多次了
It helps lovely tourists, such as yourself...
這能幫你這種外來客放鬆...
...loosen up without impairing your ability to stay awake...
讓人整晚都能保持清醒...
...and have guilt -free, vigorous sex with me.
又毫無罪惡感的跟我上床
- Wow. - I' m sorry.
-哇 -抱歉
I'm not a cliff diver, either. I'm afraid of heights.
我也不是跳崖手 我有懼高症
Well, since it's my last night in town...
今天是我假期的最後一晚...
...can I pretend you didn't just say that and still have sex with you anyway?
我能不能假裝沒聽到這些 然後還是跟你上床？
I can't do it. I' m sorry.
我做不到，對不起
Well, can you at least point me in the direction of someone who can?
至少幫忙指點一下有誰能吧
That guy over there could help you out.
那邊那傢伙應該幫得上忙
- Isn't that a woman? - Jeez, I' m not really sure.
-那不是個女人嗎？ -我不太確定耶
But you're too drunk to notice, remember? Take care.
但你已醉到搞不清了，對吧？ 保重
- Hey, you. Aloha. - Aloha.
-你，阿囉哈 -阿囉哈
Not aloha, "hello," aloha, "goodbye." We're closed today. Go away.
這個阿囉哈不是你好，是再見 今天沒開店，走開
- What are you talking about? - Order up!
-你在說什麼啊？ -上菜了！
- Don't move. I have to talk to you. - Okay.
-別動，我有話要跟你說 -知道啦
- Hey! Tattoo-Face! - Hey, Peanut Butter Cups!
-大花臉！ -花生巧克力男！
Hi.
嗨
My fingers are extra fishy today, if you care to take a whiff.
我手指今天更腥了，想聞嗎？
What was that?
你說什麼？
I was petting my walrus all morning and thinking of you the whole time.
我早上幫海象擦澡 滿腦子想的都是你
Okay, pervert. I think that you should leave.
變態狂，我想你該走了
What? I was joking because of what we talked about yesterday.
我開玩笑啦，我們昨天聊過的
Yesterday?
昨天？
I've never even met you.
我根本沒見過你
- Nick! I need help! - Coming, Lucy.
-大胖，快來幫我 -來了
Nick, put that down. I'll handle it.
大胖，放下，我來處理
- You, follow me. - Wait a... What's going on?
-你跟我來 -怎麼回事？
I was kidding around with you!
我是開玩笑的啦！
What's happening here? Is she crazy or something?
搞什麼？她是不是瘋了？
Lucy is a very special person. Very different from other people.
露西很特別 她跟別人很不一樣
Okay.
好
About a year ago, Lucy was in a terrible car accident.
一年前，露西出了車禍
She and her father went up North Shore to get a pineapple.
她跟她爸去北邊摘鳳梨
Her father broke some ribs, but Lucy suffered a serious head injury.
她爸斷了幾根肋骨 但露西卻有嚴重的腦部傷害
She lost her short-term memory.
她喪失了短期記憶的能力
So she can't remember anything?
所以她啥都記不得了？
No, no, no, she has all of her long-term memory.
不，她的長期記憶都還在
That's a different part of the brain.
那屬於不同的腦部區塊
Her whole life, up to the night before the accident, she remembers.
她這一輩子 到出意外前一晚，她都記得
She just can't retain any new information.
她只是無法再輸入任何新資訊
It's like her slate gets wiped clean every night while she sleeps.
她每晚睡著後就從新開始
Hold on. This sounds like something I would tell a psycho girl...
這很像我跟瘋女人分手的借口...
...so she'd stop calling me. Am I the psycho girl
好讓她別再纏我 我像瘋子嗎？
I wish I was making this up!
我沒有半句假話！
She has no memory that she ever met you.
她不記得她見過你
What about the pineapple -picking thing?
那摘鳳梨的事呢？
She says that every day, because each morning...
她每天都提，因為她每天醒來...
...she wakes up thinking it's October 13th of last year.
就認為今天是去年10月13日
She comes for breakfast because that's what she did on Sundays...
她會來吃早餐 因為她每週日都這樣...
...and October 13th was a Sunday.
10月13日剛好就是週日
She has no idea it's more than a year later.
她不知道已經過一年了
She reads the newspaper.
她會看報紙
It's a special paper her father puts on their porch.
那是她爸特別準備的報紙
It's from the day of her accident. He got hundreds of them printed.
那是她出意外那天的報紙 他準備了好幾百份
Lucy does the same thing every day.
露西每天都做一樣的事
- Hello! - Back here.
-嘿！ -在後面
- Hi, Dad! - Oh, hi, sweetie.
-老爸！ -小公主
You got one without me.
你沒等我就去摘了
The lady at the farmers' market gave it to me as a birthday present.
市場的小姐送我當生日禮物
I didn't wanna hurt her feelings.
我不想傷她的心
I think she likes you.
我想她喜歡你
- Yeah, what's not to like? - What about our tradition?
-我是人見人愛 -那我們的傳統呢？
Well, I have another idea. I painted my workshop yesterday.
我有主意，我昨天漆了工作室
White.
一片雪白
Now it's too white. Gives me a headache.
可是它太白了，白的讓我頭痛
Oh, yeah, you definitely need some color in here.
是啊，你需要加點色彩
Well, you know, that's what I was thinking.
我也這麼想
- Really? - Yeah. Go nuts.
-真的？ -是啊，用力揮灑吧
- Paint me something for my birthday. - I will.
-劃點好看的給我當生日禮物 -沒問題
And promise that we can pick a pineapple for Thanksgiving, okay?
答應我，感恩節一起去摘鳳梨
- Sounds great. - Okay, good.
-很好
Hey, you should watch the Vikings game while I' m painting.
我作劃，你去看海盜隊比賽吧
Good idea.
好主意
- Yeah, baby. Isolate. - What are we eating tonight, Doug?
-好耶，硬起來吧 -兒子，今晚吃什麼？
- Spaghetti, Pop. - Try not to sweat in the sauce.
-意大利面 -別把汗滴進肉醬裡
Sorry, Pop.
歹勢，老爸
Go Vikings.
加油，海盜隊
Seven hundred and five. Seven hundred and six.
七百零五、七百零六
- Seven hundred and seven. - Hey, you guys.
-七百零七 -兩位帥哥
Hey, sweetie. How's the painting coming?
小公主，劃的怎樣了？
- You'll see. - Cool
-等著瞧吧 -太好了
- Oh. What's the score? - The Vikings are on the two-yard line.
-比數如何？ -海盜隊還差兩碼...
- Lf they score, they bring it to 14-10. - Maybe they'll win for your birthday.
-就逆轉勝了 -也許你生日他們會贏球
And I' II bet Culpepper runs it in.
我賭克裴會直接達陣得分
I'll bet he fakes a handoff to Williams, throws to Kleinsasser in the end zone.
我賭他會假裝交球給威廉 然後傳球給達陣區的柯蘭
- Loser does the dishes? - You're on.
-輸的人洗碗？ -沒問題
- Keep the offense on the field.
讓防守的一隊無法得分
Culpepper fakes a handoff to Williams. He will throw.
克裴假傳給威廉，他會傳球
He's got Kleinsasser in the end zone! Touchdown, Minnesota.
柯蘭在達陣區，達陣得分
Doug, you're good.
老弟，你真行
Maybe you should be a coach.
也許你該去當教練
- Dad. - Moron!
-阿爸 -你去死啦！
That hurt.
很痛耶
And you don't look a day over 25.
你看來只有25歲
Yeah, right, and Doug's muscles aren't pharmaceutically enhanced.
是哦，你弟的肌肉還是真的咧
What? I use an herb supplement...
你說什麼？
...that can be purchased at any health-food store. Check this out.
我只吃過購物頻道的猛虎丸 你看看
Check out these glutes. Rock-hard, baby.
看看我的臀肌，超硬挺的
Pretty sweet, huh?
猛吧？
Stop it! You're gonna make me throw up on the cake.
別鬧了 別害我吐在蛋糕上
Okay, just open your present.
好，拆禮物吧
Okay. Let's see what we've got here.
看看這是什麼
The Sixth Sense.
《靈異第六感》
Hey! When I' m done doing the dishes, do you guys wanna watch it?
我去洗碗，你們就放來看吧
- Sure.
-好啊
Ben Friedkin?
班佛萊迪？
Some people, they call me freak.
有些人叫我怪胎
- Ronald Sumner? - I am. I am a freak. Look at me.
-朗諾桑□？ -我的確是怪胎
Just give me a chance...
給我一次機會...
I can't believe it. Bruce Willis is a ghost.
我真不敢相信 布魯斯威利竟然是鬼
I'm shocked. Did you see that coming?
我被嚇到了，你們有想到嗎？
- No. - Not a clue.
-想都沒想到
- Shocked as hell. - Anyway, it was awesome.
-我也嚇到了 -真的很好看
- Happy birthday. - Love you, Sis.
-生日快樂 -我愛你，老姐
Your muscles are getting so big, I can barely wrap my arms around you.
你練的好壯 我都快抱不住你了
You like that? Check this out.
喜歡嗎？你看看
Okay, okay! Enough with the titty dance! Let your sister go to sleep.
好了，別再跳奶子舞了 讓你姐去睡吧
- I like it. - Sweet dreams, Lucy.
-我喜歡 -祝你好夢，老姐
- Good night.
-晚安
Hey, Tracy, how you doing?
翠西，你好嗎？
Yeah?
是嗎？
Well, things changed a little bit since high school
高中畢業後我變了很多
And this is what happens every single day.
這是每天都一再發生的事
How long it gonna take for her memory to come back?
她的記憶多久會恢復？
Her doctors say it may never come back.
她的醫生說永遠不可能
So, basically, what you're saying is...
所以基本上，這一切表示...
...she's perfect for you. - What do you mean?
-她超適合你的 -這話什麼意思？
You can hang out all day with no attachment, because...
你可以跟她混卻不用負責
Her plane leaves every night? There's a problem with that.
她每天重開機，只有個問題...
- What is? - It 's evil
-什麼問題？ -這太邪惡了
No, it isn't.
才不咧
You meet her, hang out, flirt, no commitment, nobody gets hurt.
你跟她約會、遊玩 沒承諾，大家都不會受傷
- She's got brain damage, you psycho. - Okay, I' II give you that one.
-她腦子受了傷，死花癡 -我承認這點
But I think it'd be healthy for you.
但我以為這對你很不錯
You haven't allowed yourself to connect with a girl
你多年來都不肯固定下來
I appreciate your interest, but leave me alone.
感謝你關心，阿嬤，少煩我
Hey, you'd be doing exactly what her father does:
你這麼做跟她爸一模一樣
Giving her a wonderful day.
讓她每天都很愉快
When it's time for you to go on your big boat trip, poof, you just leave.
然後你上路旅行去也 咻一下！你就走了
She'll never even know you're gone.
她根本不會知道你走了
I'm not sure about the "poofing" part, because I' m not a good poofer.
我不太確定「咻」那部份 因為我不太會用「咻」的
Demonstrate a good poof for me?
你能不能「咻」給我看
Quit busting my coconuts for five seconds.
關我粉鳥什麼事？
All right. Would you stop poofing on that joint and do some work?
好，拜託你少咻一點 做點正事吧？
Okay. Let's get this sucker ready.
來修好這艘船吧
Then we're gonna take her out for a spin.
接著我們試開一下
Captain's log: November 7 th. Nearly midnight.
船長日誌，11月7日午夜
The Sea Serpent is fully recovered from her mishap...
海蛇號終於修好...
...and ready to once again brave the open ocean.
再度準備航向大海
I think my stitches opened up again, cuz.
我想我的傷口又開了
You got a cat? Because I feel something licking me.
你有養貓？有東西在舔我
How is it?
你好
Peanut Butter Cups. What are you doing here?
花生巧克力男，你幹嘛？
I just wanted to say hi to Lucy.
我想跟露西打個招呼
I promise you I' m not gonna do anything wrong.
我保證不會亂來
What did Sue say?
阿蘇怎麼說？
She said that if I talk to Lucy, you'll kill me with a meat cleaver.
她說要是我跟露西說話 你會用菜刀把我剁成肉醬
She's the boss, cuz. But don't worry.
她說了算，但是別擔心
Lucy probably didn't wanna talk to you anyway.
露西可能也不想跟你說話
- What does that mean? - This ain't a disco.
-這話什麼意思？ -這裡又不是舞廳
She doesn't want guys hitting on her during her breakfast.
她吃早餐時可不想被人搭訕
She does if it's Henry Roth.
羅亨利出馬就不同
- Who that? - Who that? Me that.
-誰？ -誰？我啦
I bet you 20 bucks I can get her to have breakfast with me again.
賭20元能讓她跟我共進早餐
- You're on. - I love it.
-我賭了 -很好
- How you doing, honey? - Hey, Sue. Nice haircut.
-你好，小乖 -你好，阿蘇，好美的髮型
Oh, mahalo. See you in a bit.
謝謝，回頭見
Nick and I have an arrangement. You can trust me.
我跟大胖自有安排，相信我
Don't worry.
別擔心
You should try this out. Put it in there.
你該試試這樣，把這放進來
Swivelly door.
旋轉門
Waffleonians can come in and out now.
這樣鬆餅人就可以進出自如
Are you from a country where it's okay to stick your fingers...
你媽是不是從小教你...
...all over someone else's food?
用手指摸別人的食物？
No, I' m from this country.
沒，我媽沒這麼教
Why? Were you gonna eat that? Oh.
你要吃這些？
All right, well, have a good meal
祝你早餐愉快
- Yeah. - That was pathetic.
-沒錯 -真差勁
Yeah? Why don't you choke on your Spam?
你怎麼沒被火腿噎死啊？
Double or nothing tomorrow.
明天賭雙倍
Hey. I' m sorry to bother you...
很抱歉打擾你...
...but you look like a person who appreciates fine art...
你看來似乎對藝術很有品味...
...so I wanted your opinion.
我想聽聽你的看法
I drew this. It 's a picture of a father and son fishing off a fishing boat.
我劃了這個，這幅圖 是父子在船上釣魚
There's a walrus right there...
這裡有只海象...
Oh, you don't speak English. Okay.
你不會說英文啊
Doesn't look Chinese.
看來不像中國人啊
Forty.
40塊錢了
Can I have that?
那能不能給我？
I need something to wipe my ass with.
我上廁所有用
Shut up.
閉嘴啦
I wonder what's the matter with him.
不知道他是怎麼了
Looks like a stupid asshole to me.
我看他倒像個笨蛋
Excuse me. Okay. I didn't mean to startle you.
歹勢，我無意嚇著你
- No, that's all right. L- - - Are you okay?
-沒關係 -你沒事吧？
Yeah, I' m fine. I' m having a problem with something...
我很好，我只是有點問題...
Something that I could help you with?
我能幫得上忙嗎？
No, no, no. I just...
不行，我...
...can't read.
不識字啦
You gotta be kidding me.
不會吧
- I can read that for you. - No. Thank you.
-我可以幫忙念菜單給你聽 -謝謝
I can do this on my own.
我可以自己來
Appreciate the sentiment.
謝謝你的好意
I'm gonna get an order of the...
我要點...
Pan...
煎...
Panku...
煎冰...
Ca...
餅...
Panclocks.
煎冰
- Pancakes. - Okay, I' II have pancake.
-煎餅 -好，我點煎餅
- Pancah... Pancakes! Pancakes!
-煎餅、煎餅
- I' m so stupid! - Oh, don't cry.
-我好蠢，蠢斃了 -別哭嘛
- Stupid. Stupid. Stupid. - Don't cry.
-我真蠢，我真無知 -別哭啦
- I don't know anything! - What a loser.
-我是白癡！ -窩囊廢
I'll tell you what. Why don't you sit with me?
你過來跟我一起坐吧？
You can have some breakfast and I'll help teach you some of the words.
你吃早餐，我教你認字
- Okay. - All right.
-好吧 -很好
- That sounds nice. - Come on over.
-聽來不錯 -過來吧
- Okay, thank you. - All right.
-謝謝 -不客氣
So I comes before the E?
所以I都在E後面？
- Except after C? - Yes.
-遇到C時才例外？ -對
Okay, and C is that little half a squiggly one, right?
C是右邊有缺口的那個？
- Yes. - I think I' m getting it.
-我想我懂了
- How'd you get so good at teaching? - I' m a teacher. I do it all the time.
-你怎麼這麼會教人？ -我是老師，教書是我的工作
I'm an art teacher at the Haluki-liki Junior High.
我在哈蘭國中當美術老師
Well, you Haluki-liki the kind of teacher all the kids have crushes on.
你是那種學生會很哈的老師
I know I would if I was in your class.
是我就會
Okay.
好吧
Oh, boy, do my... My fingers smell like fish.
老天... 我的手魚腥味真重
That doesn't gross you out, does it?
這不會令你作嘔吧？
No, not at all.
一點也不
Really?
真的？
If Lucy gets hurt, I' m gonna chop you with the meat cleaver.
要是露西受傷，你就死定了
Okay, okay.
好啦
So I had a nice time.
我過的很愉快
- Yeah, me too. - Thank you very much.
-是啊，我也是 -非常感謝你
- Let me get it for you. - Thank you.
-我幫你開 -謝了
Sure.
沒問題
Okay.
坐穩了
I just want to eat you up, tomorrow and the next day, next day, next day...
我想把你吃了 明天、後天、大後天...
I'll see you around.
改天見了
Okay.
好
Really? That's it?
真的？就這樣？
- That's what? - All that flirting...
-就怎樣？ -你想盡辦法搭訕...
...and phony "I can't read" stuff, and you're not gonna ask me out...
還假裝不識字...
...or for my phone number?
卻連我的電話號碼也不問？
- I can't read. - Oh, shut up.
-我是不識字 -少來了
That was one of the goofiest things I've ever seen, but I thought:
這是我見過最蠢的招數了 但我想...
"Hey, if this guy is so desperate to meet me...
要是這傢伙真這麼想認識我...
...he might be worth talking to."
也許值得跟他聊聊
But then I get stiffed.
結果我被騙了
No, no, no, this is what happened. I...
不，事情是這樣的...
Mahalo for the ego boost.
真有你的
- You're right. You're right. I feel like... - No worries.
-你說的對，我覺得... -我無所謂
I gotta... I can read a little!
我是識一點字
I didn't know I came before E! That one I didn't know, I swear.
我不知道I都在E後面 這點我真的不知道
Oh, you idiot.
超級白癡
I hope you're happy, Shamu.
這下你高興了吧，死胖子
Marlin. It 's Sue.
馬林，我是阿蘇
- Oh, aloha, sir. My name's Henry... - I know who you are.
-阿囉哈，先生，我叫亨利... -我知道你是誰
- I want to apologize to your daughter. - Not gonna happen.
-我想向你女兒道歉 -不必了
She's inside. We're gonna straighten things out.
她在裡面，讓我們把話講清楚
Dad, the damn mongoose got in the garbage again!
阿爸，野狗又來翻垃圾了
- Is this the guy? - Yeah.
-就是這傢伙？ -對
Mr. Roth, I have one simple request:
羅先生，我有個小請求
Stay away from my daughter.
離我女兒遠點
Absolutely. I hurt her feelings and don't want it to end like that.
當然，不過我傷了她的感情 我不想這樣結束
It's gonna end like this.
就是會這樣結束
Calm down, little fellow.
冷靜點，小傢伙
I'm gonna kill you! You're a dead man. Okay, I' m calm.
我要宰了你，你死定了 好了，我很冷靜了
I'm calm.
我很冷靜了
- Let me help you up. - I got it! I got it.
-我幫你起來 -我自己來！我自己來
It's just Dad and I work too hard to protect Lucy to let some idiot ruin it.
我爸和我很努力保護露西 以免盯上她的蒼蠅毀了一切
I know what you guys do and I totally respect that.
我知道你們的努力，我很敬佩
If you know her condition, you know she can't have a normal relationship.
那你就知道她不能有正常關係
The next morning, she won't know who he is.
因為她第二天就會忘了他是誰
And any guy who's okay with that...
不介意這點的人...
...ain't okay with me.
我可不歡迎
- I' m not looking for a one-night stand. - Anything with Lucy is, numb-nuts.
-我不是尋求一夜情 -露西有的只是一夜情
Give us a break. Just stay away from the Hukilau Cafe.
幫個忙，別去阿蘇小吃店了
My daughter's been through enough.
我女兒已經夠苦了
Okay. I' m sorry.
好吧，對不起
I could have whooped his ass, but this gravel, I slipped on it...
阿爸，我沒法痛扁他 都是因為這堆碎石頭害我滑倒
Yeah, well, maybe you need to do a few more butt flexes.
也許你該多鍛煉你的屁屁
Cheap shot, Dad.
阿爸，你好低級
So fresh and so clean.
清新又舒爽
Hey, Alexa, did you hook up with that girl from the bar?
你那晚在酒吧有上那個妞嗎？
- I chickened out. - Really?
-我打了退堂鼓 -真的？
Yeah, I don't know. I guess I prefer sausage to taco.
我想我喜歡香腸，不愛蛤仔
- What? - Yeah. No, I agree, buddy.
-怎樣？ -我同意
Get out of here. Run for the hills.
快逃吧
Let me ask you something, Alexa.
我問你個問題
If you promised a girl' s dad that you wouldn't see her...
要是你答應一個美眉的老爸 你不會再見她了...
...would you consider that a binding promise?
你會認真守信嗎？
- Absolutely. - Yeah?
-當然 -是嗎？
Then again, there are always ways around such things.
但詛咒也是有辦法破解的
- Like? - For example...
-比方說？ -比方說...
...if I promised a woman's father I would not see her...
要是我答應她老爸我不見她...
...I would simply shut my eyes while she serviced my manhood.
她幫我吹簫時，我就閉眼裝瞎
That's actually a cool way to look at it.
那樣做不錯
And a very gross way.
不過有點低級
He asked me not to go to the Hukilau. I'm not going there.
他要我別去小吃店，我就不去
I'm not doing anything wrong.
我才不會犯錯咧
Sorry to bother you. I'm kind of stuck here.
抱歉打擾你，我拋錨了
- Car trouble? - Yeah. You mind giving me a jump?
-車子出狀況？ -借個電發車吧？
Okay.
好了
Appreciate your time.
謝謝你幫忙
Not everybody would have stopped.
不是每個人都會跟你一樣
- You're real sweet. - Oh, yeah. Thank you.
-你真好心 -謝謝
I can't believe you fell for that.
你不會這麼好騙吧
Well, my grandfather died trying to jump-start a car.
我爺爺就是這樣被電死的
I'm sorry. I was just joking around.
對不起，我是開玩笑的
I can't believe you fell for that!
你不會這麼好騙吧！
Oh, my God.
老天
That was very good.
你演技真好
- My name's Henry. - I' m Lucy.
-我叫亨利 -我是露西
Nice to meet you. You look like a nice...
幸會，你看起來是個好...
Hi. Sorry for the delay. Should be a few minutes.
抱歉耽誤了你，一下就好
- No problem. No worries. - Where you coming from?
-沒問題，別擔心 -你從哪來的？
Breakfast?
剛吃完早餐？
- Yeah. - How was it?
-對 -好吃嗎？
I had waffles. They were delicious.
我吃了鬆餅，很好吃
Ilike making little houses out of waffles.
我喜歡拿鬆餅蓋小房子
- You do? - That's my thing.
-真的？ -我超愛的
- What's your name? - Lucy.
-你叫什麼名字？ -露西
Hi, I' m Henry.
我是亨利
Okay, pal When she stops, just let her pet you. Look cute.
等她停車，就裝可愛讓她摸
Go to the middle of the road. Thank you. Right there. Perfect.
到路中央去，很好
- Oh, shit. - Here she comes. Smile.
-糟了 -她來了，笑一個
Where is she?
她人呢？
Oh, my God. Oh, no!
阿娘喂！
Okay. That didn't work.
沒用
Shit your pants? So did I
挫賽了？我也一樣
Okay, this is her. Start beating me up.
她來了，快打我
Make it look good.
裝像一點
Give me your wallet!
把皮夾給我！
Okay, haole, what do you think? You can come to this island...
白毛豬，你少肖想了...
...eat our pineapple... - Help me! Not so hard.
-跑來這裡吃喝玩樂 -救命！別太大力
- Take it easy. - Try to bang our women.
-輕一點 -還想把我們的美眉
Making my sister clean your hotel room.
讓我妹幫你清掃房間
Okay. What's that have to do with this? Relax.
那跟這有什麼關係？輕一點
- Hey! Hey! Help me, please! - Stupid haole!
-救命啊！ -死白毛豬！
Yeah, that's right. Take that! And that! And that!
好啊，你找死、找死...
You got him. You got him. Enough. Enough.
你教訓夠了，好了
- Are you okay? - Yes, yes...
-你沒事吧？ -沒事...
Okay, I' II be back. Come here!
我馬上回來，你給我過來
No, no! I think he's had enough.
不，他被你打夠了
I'm sorry.
歹勢啦
My eye!
我的眼睛！
- You got him! - Not good enough!
-你教訓到他了！ -還不夠呢！
Oh, Kamehameha!
三太子救命啊！
He learned his lesson!
他得到教訓了！
- What's your name? - My name's Henry.
-你叫什麼名字？ -亨利
- You did good. - Hi. Sorry.
-你真行 -抱歉
I'm in a community-watch program...
我是守望相助隊隊員...
Oh, you crazy bitch!
你這個肖查某！
Yeah, keep running!
是啊，快跑吧！
Okay, okay, he's... He's gone now.
好了，他走了
Not her. False alarm.
不是她，假警報
Don't worry, I called the cops already. I'm all set.
別擔心，我報警了，我沒事
Yeah? You all set for this, Mr. Smarty?
是嗎？你真會演戲啊，大天才
- Oh, shit. - Yeah.
-靠！ -對啊
When you're finished playing your kidnap-victim crap on my daughter...
等你演完綁架戲以後...
...come by the house.
來我們家一趟
Okay.
好
Oh, boy.
媽呀
There's something I wanna show you.
我要讓你看樣東西
We figured it out. She only sings on days she meets you.
她只在遇見你的日子唱這首歌
You're kidding me. That song?
不會吧，那首歌？
That's Mom and Dad's song.
那是我爸媽的歌
When her mom was alive, Lucy would have me take that tape...
她母親在世時，要是我出海...
...on every fishing trip I went on. - Oh, yeah?
-她會要我帶海灘男孩的錄音帶 -是嗎？
Yeah, she knew it would make me miss her mom...
她知道這會讓我想她母親...
...and want to come home sooner.
讓我一心只想快點回家
I'm seeing a new side to you, sir. I gotta tell you, it's grossing me out.
真看不出來，你竟然這麼噁心
Let me ask you something.
我問你
What's in it for you? What do you get out of this?
你有啥目的？ 你這樣有啥好處？
I don't know.
我不知道
Wouldn't you want to spend an hour a day with that?
你們難道不想享受一下？
Actually, no. She sings like shit.
才不呢，她歌聲超爛
- What? - Can I ask you guys something?
-怎樣？ -請問一下
What'll happen down the line? Someday she'll wake up...
以後會怎樣？ 有天她會醒來...
...look in the mirror and notice she aged 10 years overnight.
看著鏡子 注意到自己一夜老了十歲
You know something, Henry?
你知道嗎？
I worry about that every damn day of my life.
我每天都擔心這一刻的來到
Pardon me.
抱歉
Sorry to interrupt, but I noticed we were both eating alone...
我無意打擾你 但我注意到我們都是一個人...
...and I thought I could sit with you, maybe build a syrup Jacuzzi...
我想也許我能跟你一起坐...
...for your waffle house? - Oh, that would be nice...
-我能幫你的鬆餅屋蓋糖漿泳池 -那是不錯啦...
...but I have a boyfriend.
不過我有男友了
So I' m sorry.
真抱歉
You're making up a boyfriend to get rid of me?
你用這當借口趕我走？
No, I' m not.
我才沒有
What's his name, then?
那他叫什麼名字？
Ringo.
林哥
Is his last name Starr?
他不會剛好姓史塔吧？
- No. McCartney. - McCartney, okay.
-不是，他姓麥卡尼 -好吧
- Oh, no. - All right. I' m sorry.
-不會吧 -好吧，對不起
No! This cop is writing me a ticket!
不是啦！條子在開我單子！
Oh, whoa, whoa. I wouldn't go out there.
是我就不會出去
- Wait, wait, wait! - Go on!
-等等 -快去啊！
I'm coming.
我來了
The tags don't expire for seven months.
我的牌照還有7個月才到期
- They expired May of this year. - No! No, no!
-它今年5月已經過期了 -不對...
They expire May of next year.
是明年5月才到期
I think there's been a misunderstanding.
我想這裡有點誤會
- I don't. - This is ridiculous.
-我可沒有 -這太扯了
I'm not paying for this! It's October!
現在是10月
Excuse me. Can I borrow this? Look, October!
借我一下，你看，10月！
Lucy, let's go back inside.
我們進去吧
What?
什麼？
Having a bad day, Doug!
凸槌了，兒子
Sweetheart...
小公主...
...these are from the accident.
這些是車禍的照片
Oh, no!
不會吧！
I can feel it.
我感覺的到
You were in the hospital for three months, sweetheart.
你在醫院裡待了3個月
I have to talk to this doctor. I need to hear it from him.
我要跟醫生談談 我要聽他親自跟我說
You have heard it, sweetie. Many times.
你已經聽過很多次了
I have?
是嗎？
I'll take her.
我帶她去
I have to hear for myself too.
我也想親耳聽聽
Doug, just take this, okay? I can't...
小弟，這個拿去 我沒辦法...
I can't look at it anymore.
我沒辦法再看下去了
- It 's gonna be all right, Luce. - Don't call me Luce. I barely know you.
-不會有事的，小露 -別叫我小露，我跟你又不熟
Sweetie, you're sort of dating him.
女兒，你跟他算是情侶
Sorry I' m not better-looking.
抱歉我長的不夠帥
What else happened since last October?
我車禍後發生了什麼事？
- What about my students? - Miss Campbell took over your class.
-我的學生呢？ -坎老師接手你的課
- Did Alicia marry that guy? - Yeah.
-艾莉嫁給那個人了？ -對
Doug, did you win the Mr. Hawaii contest?
你贏得夏威夷健美先生了嗎？
I didn't know there was gonna be a urine test.
我不知道他們會驗尿
Wow.
糟糕
Do we have sex?
我們上過床嗎？
No, we don't. Just so everybody knows that.
沒，大家都聽清楚了
We want to.
我們很想
Just kidding.
開玩笑的啦
So you guys have to just lie to me every day.
所以你們每天都要撒謊騙我？
Hey, Lucy. Good to see you again.
露西，真高興再見到你
What the hell 's her problem?
她有什麼問題啊？
She doesn't remember who you are, brah.
她不記得你是誰
Oh, yeah.
對哦
I suck at this job.
這工作真爛
Lucy, these are your brain scans here.
這是你的腦部掃瞄結果
I'm afraid they show no improvement.
恐怕並沒有什麼進展
The temporal lobe was severely damaged.
顳葉在車禍中受損嚴重
What we believe is scar tissue here is impairing your ability...
我們認為是傷疤的組織 阻擋你在睡眠中...
...to convert short-term memory into long-term memory while you sleep.
將短期記憶 轉換為長期記憶的能力
The condition's come to be known as Goldfield Syndrome.
這症狀稱為金氏症候群
- Who's Goldfield? - A brilliant Lithuanian psychiatrist.
-金氏是指誰？ -一位立陶宛的天才精神病學家
He himself suffered temporal-lobe damage.
他也受顳葉損傷所苦
Took him four years to publish his findings...
他花了4年時間才出版論文...
...because he had to keep starting over from scratch.
因為他老是得從頭開始寫
Obviously, your sense of humor is still intact, and that's here.
顯然你的幽默感沒事，在這裡
Magnificent amygdala as well.
偉大的扁桃體
- Doctor, I have a question. - I' d be happy to answer it...
-醫生，我有個問題 -我很樂意回答...
...but as I' ve told you before, this is a hygienic facility. Shirts are required.
我說過這裡是醫療場所 在辦公室裡要穿上衣
- Oh, okay. - Nice move.
-好啦 -幹的好
Listen, doctor, this...
醫生...
...friend of mine's been experimenting a little with steroids.
我有個朋友 他服用了一點點的類固醇
He's been having a lot of wet dreams.
而他老是會夢遺
Could there be a connection between them?
這兩者之間可不可能有關連？
Douglas, get off the juice.
道格，別再用禁藥了
As for the nocturnal emissions, why don't you take a swim...
至於晚上會發射的問題，去游泳...
...buy a shirt with no holes, find a wahine and take her to dinner.
買件沒洞的T恤 約個漂亮美眉去吃晚餐
I'll tell my friend you said so.
我會跟我朋友講
In any case, Lucy, your condition is stable...
露西，你的狀況很穩定...
...but most likely permanent.
可能也不會變好了
I'm so sorry, dear.
抱歉
But it could be worse.
還有可能會變糟
Yeah? How?
是嗎？多糟？
I think you should meet Ten Second Tom.
我想你該見見「十秒湯姆」
Callahan Institute is the leading brain-injury clinic in the Pacific Rim.
卡拉漢療養院 是最先進的腦傷醫療院所
We are funded out of Sandusky, Ohio by T.B. Callahan...
本院由卡拉漢先生資助建立...
...the automotive-components tycoon and philanthropist.
他是偉大的富豪慈善家
And now, I would like to introduce to you...
各位，請各位見過...
...our most distinguished clinical subject...
我們最出名的病人...
...Tom.
湯姆
- Hi. I' m Tom. - Henry.
-你好，我是湯姆 -亨利
- Marlin. - Doug.
-馬林 -道格
- Lucy. - Hi.
-露西 -嗨
Cool flip-flops. Where'd you get them?
真棒的涼鞋，哪買的？
You like those? It 's interesting. I was on the North Shore...
這很有趣，我當時在北灘...
Hi, I' m Tom.
你好，我是湯姆
- Henry. - Hi.
-亨利 -嗨
- Marlin. - Tom lost part of his brain...
-馬林 -湯姆因為打獵意外傷及腦部...
...in a hunting accident. His memory lasts 10 seconds.
他的記憶只能撐十秒
I was in an accident? That's terrible.
我出過意外？真可怕
Don't worry. You'll get over it in seconds.
沒關係，過三秒你就忘了
Get over it? I mean, what happened? Did I get shot in the brain?
怎麼？我頭部中槍了？
- Hi, I' m Tom. - Hi, I' m Lucy.
-你好，我是湯姆 -你好，我是露西
- Hi. - Doug.
-嗨 -我是道格
- Hey. - Marlin.
-馬林
Hey, Tom, can I tell you a secret?
湯姆，告訴你一個秘密
Don't you think you're a little old to still have wet dreams?
你怎麼這麼大還會夢遺？
- They liked that. - Hi, I' m Tom.
-他們喜歡耶 -你好，我是湯姆
- Yeah, watch yourself, Tom. - Easy.
-你給我小心點，湯姆 -別激動
- I' m gonna go to sleep. - All right. Good night.
-我要去睡了 -晚安
Good night, you guys. I'll see you tomorrow.
晚安，明天見了
- And I guess I' II see you too? - Oh, yeah.
-我還會再見到你吧？ -會的
You had a rough day today. I'm sorry.
你今天辛苦了，對不起
I hope you get some rest tonight.
好好休息吧
Okay.
我會的
Good night.
晚安
So how you getting home?
你怎麼回家？
- You gonna take the Likelike or... - Hey.
-你要走莉琪公路... -喂
Thank you for being so nice to me today.
謝謝你今天對我這麼好
- Sure. - I don't want you to...
-沒問題 -我不希望...
...strike out tomorrow.
你明天不來了
So maybe you could talk to me about...
也許你該跟我談...
...lilies.
百合花
Lilies?
百合花？
I'm a sucker for lilies.
我超愛百合花的
Thanks for the tip.
謝謝你的提示
Good night.
晚安
My, oh, my.
好耶
- Lover-boy. - Yes, sir.
-大情聖 -是的，先生
You don't have to rush off. Stick around.
你若沒別的事要做
You've earned yourself a couple beers.
可以進來喝幾杯
So what'll you do when you finish the boat?
船弄好後，你打算怎樣？
Actually, I' m going on a trip soon...
我要去旅行一陣子...
...to study undersea Pacific walrus behaviors.
研究海象的水中行為
Sounds kind of fruity.
真是個偷窺狂
- Thank you. - How long is it gonna take?
-多謝讚美 -打算去多久？
About a year.
大約一年
Guess you won't miss days like this.
你一定不會想念這種日子
Well, maybe days like this don't have to be so bad.
這種日子也許並不壞
What are you trying to say?
你想說什麼？
When you guys tell her...
當你們告訴她真相時...
...she's not just finding out about the accident.
她不只是發現那次意外事故
She's finding out that her life is basically a setup.
還發現她的生活都只是騙局
I think that freaks her out the most.
我想這是最讓她抓狂的
- You're an expert now? - No.
-你成了專家啦？ -沒有
I'm saying I wish there was another way besides:
我只是希望能別老是說
"Sorry we couldn't trick you today. Here's pictures of your broken head."
「很抱歉今天沒法騙你 這是你撞破腦袋的照片」
- You want a broken head? - You'll give him one?
-你想被打破頭嗎？ -怎麼，你想扁他？
No, Daddy, I thought you was gonna do it.
沒啦，我以為你要開扁
Nobody's gotta break my head. I'm gonna split anyways.
不用麻煩，我反正要走了
Oh, don't go just because my son is psychotic.
別因為我兒子發神經走人
Good night. Sweet dreams. Keep them dry there, Doug.
晚安，睡覺別亂開炮了
Very funny.
真愛說笑
- Excuse me. Lucy Whitmore? - Yes?
-失禮，惠露西？ -我是
I have a delivery for you.
有人送東西給你
- A delivery for me? - Yes.
-給我的？ -對
Oh, they're beautiful
好美
- Who are they from? - That I can't tell you.
-誰送的？ -我不能告訴你
It's a secret admirer. He also wants you to have this.
是個愛慕者，他還送你這個
- Who's your friend, Lucy? - Oh, well, I mean, I don't know.
-你朋友是誰？ -我不知道
We just met, but look.
我們才剛認識，你看！
I have a secret admirer.
有人偷偷愛慕我呢
Oh, really? What's this?
真的？這是什麼？
It's a videotape.
錄影帶
A videotape of what?
內容是什麼？
I have no idea.
我不知道
But I have to find out.
但我會看個明白
Happy birthday, Daddy.
生日快樂，阿爸
- Thank you, sweetie. - That's right. Happy birthday, sir.
-謝謝你，女兒 -生日快樂
- What are you, 200 today? - That's cute.
-你200歲了吧？ -愛說笑
- What are you doing? - I wanted to try something different.
-你在搞什麼鬼？ -我想試點不一樣的
If it doesn't work, we've only wasted one day.
要是沒用，也不過就浪費一天
Marha Stewar faced charges...
(□莎史都華被起訴...)
Oh, God!
天哪！
Okay, I think it's on. Go. Go.
機器開了，開始吧
Aloha! I'm Henry Roth.
阿囉哈！我是羅亨利
We met here at the Hukilau Cafe about a year after your accident.
我們在你車禍後一年 在阿蘇小吃店認識
I like you and you like me, most days.
我喜歡你，你也喜歡我 大部分的日子是的
Every day is different, but basically this is what happens, Lucy.
每天都不一樣 基本上情況是這樣，露西
Kikikoloko, take the camera.
拿好攝影機
- I got it. - Don't drop it.
-拿好了 -別摔到了
Okay, all right. Here we are, right here.
好了，我們在這裡
The par of you in this reenactment...
在這裡...
...will be played by my good friend, Ula.
由我的好友芭樂扮演你
Aloha. Sorry about your brain.
阿囉哈，你腦子的事真抱歉
I had a accident too.
我也出過意外
Believe it or not, this my good eye.
你信嗎？我這隻眼睛才是好的
- We ready? - Yeah.
-準備好了？ -好了
Hi. I like that waffle teepee that you have built.
我喜歡你建的鬆餅小屋
Oh! So nice of you to notice. Please, sit down.
真高興你喜歡，坐吧
I would love to.
我很樂意
My name is Henry, by the way.
對了，我叫亨利
My name is Lucy.
我叫露西
Smell my fingers?
要不要聞我的手指？
Fish. Right on.
魚，好耶
So, Lucy, I work at an aquarium.
露西，我在水族館工作
Aquariums make me super horny.
水族館讓我超爽的
That's not funny. Don't rub those.
這不好笑，別亂揉了
Sorry, Mr. Whitmore, if you're watching.
抱歉，伯父，如果你在看的話
It's very late, and my friend's unstable.
現在很晚了 我朋友的心智又不穩定
Come on, stop with the licking! You're making me sick.
別舔了，你真噁心
Lucy, I'm sorry.
露西，對不起
Anyways, I know you wish I was making all this stuff up.
我知道你希望這是我編的
I wish I was too.
我也希望如此
But the good news is...
但是好消息是...
...so many people out there care about you:
有很多人很關心你
Your dad and Doug and a couple of your friends here at the Hukilau...
你爸和你弟 小吃店這裡的朋友...
...who have a message for you.
想跟你說話
Lucy, as you know, your mother and I were best friends.
露西，你知道你媽跟我是麻吉
That's why I promised her that I would always help look after you.
所以我答應過她 我永遠都會幫忙照顧你
Sometimes life isn't very fair...
有時人生是很不公平...
...but we still have you.
但我們還有你
Oh, and if you're wondering about this guy who's making this tape...
要是你對拍這帶子的人有懷疑...
...he's okay.
他還不錯啦
Hey, Lucy. Just so you know, since you lost your memory...
露西，順便告訴你 自你喪失記憶之後...
...I became governor of Hawaii.
我成了夏威夷的州長
No, just kidding. I'm too smar.
騙你的啦，我太聰明了
Kualaliku! Get your brother off the dishwasher!
阿弟，把你弟從洗碗機裡撈出來
So whenever you're ready, we'd all love to talk to you...
我們隨時願意跟你談...
...and answer any questions you have...
並回答你的任何問題...
...and you're the best, Lucy. Aloha.
你是最棒的，露西，阿囉哈
How many times have I watched this?
這我看過多少次了？
This is the first time.
這是第一次
Okay, she cried for about an hour. That's not too bad.
她哭了快一個小時，還不壞
I bet in another hour she'll be ready to see her friends, have lunch...
再過一小時她就能去見朋友 吃午飯...
...get her life back.
過日子
We could do this every day.
每天來一回
We'll leave it up to her.
一切由她來決定
All right.
好
So how's the cow?
那頭牛怎麼樣了？
Same as you. Every day they have to convince her she's a cow.
一樣，天天都忘記他自己是牛
Wow, look. The bark is healing.
你看，樹幹癒合了
You're gonna get there.
你也會的
I never hung out with you in the afternoon like this.
我沒跟你在下午約會過
In this lighting, man, oh, man, you look...
在這種光線下，老天，你看來...
...disgusting.
真醜
Yeah.
沒錯
I don't know how you get me to fall for that egg-shaped head every morning.
真不知道你是用什麼辦法 讓我每天都愛上你的鹹蛋頭
All I have to do is slide on my designer jeans...
我只要穿上我的名牌牛仔褲...
...and just kind of wiggle in front of you. You go nuts.
到你前面亂晃就行 你會變的很瘋狂
Why couldn't I have met you one day before the accident?
我出事前一天能認識你就好了
Don't worry, because if you hung out with me for more than one day...
別擔心，要是你跟我在一起多一天...
...you'd realize I' m a bore.
你就會受不了我
- Oh, well, I have news for you. - Yes?
-告訴你 -什麼？
It takes less than one day.
不用一天就夠了
You know something? That hurt.
真是的，好傷人
Your damaged temporal lobe is causing me pain...
你受損的大腦顳葉 讓我受苦...
...and I' m gonna get you for that.
我要你負責
Now you're dead!
你死定了！
- I can't believe you're pregnant. - I know.
-我不敢相信你懷孕了 -我知道
- And I got her on the first try. - Yeah. Easy.
-我這是一發就中 -別激動
And, Tammy, you are so thin.
譚咪，你好瘦
Thanks, Luce.
謝了，小露
And I' m so glad you finally got...
真高興...
...that gender-reassignment surgery, Jennifer. I mean, Jonathan.
你變性成功，珍妮 我是說，阿強
Mahalo.
謝謝
- Here you go, Lucy. - Thank you.
-好了，露西 -謝謝
- You're welcome. - You must be Lucy's friend.
-不客氣 -你一定是露西...
- The one who made the tape. - I think he's more than my friend.
-那個拍帶子的朋友 -我想他不只是普通朋友
- You're my boyfriend, right? - Yes, ma'am.
-你是我男朋友，對吧？ -對
So every day you help her to realize what happened...
你每天都協助她瞭解事實...
...and you wait patiently for her to be okay with it...
還耐心的等她接受這一切...
...then get her to fall in love with you again?
然後讓她再度愛上你？
Yes, ma'am.
沒錯
You asshole!
你這個死男人！
You don't even open the fricking car door for me anymore.
你現在連車門都不幫我開了
You're in trouble.
你麻煩大了
I gotta go tinkle.
我要去尿尿
Okay, so tell me a little bit more about yourself.
好吧，再多說一點你的事
Okay. Well, I' ve...
我...
...won over seven all -you-can-eat chicken-wing contests.
贏過7次吃雞翅冠軍
- Really? - Yes.
-真的？ -真的
And I' m a ballet dancer, but only in my bathroom.
我還會跳芭蕾，只在浴室跳
No, what do you want to know?
沒有啦，你想知道什麼？
Do you love me?
你愛我嗎？
I didn't mean to put you on the spot.
我無意給你壓力
I was just asking more for informational purposes.
我只是想多知道一點
It's to keep the video as up-to-date as possible.
好更新錄影帶的資訊
Sure.
當然
Well, love is a very loaded word.
愛是個意義深遠的字
Let's see. I...
我想想，我...
I go to this restaurant every morning, and I see you there, reading.
我每天早上去小吃店 看到你在那裡看書
And...
然後...
Ilove you very much.
我非常愛你
Probably more than anybody could love another person.
也許比任何人的愛情還強烈
And how do I feel about you?
那我對你的感覺呢？
You're excited about the chicken-wing thing.
你很高興我是吃雞翅冠軍
And...
還有...
...you've been dying to make out with me for some time now.
你有時候會很想跟我擁吻
Feeling better now?
感覺好多了？
Nothing beats a first kiss.
任何事都比不上初吻
There's nothing like a first kiss.
初吻是無以倫比的
That's what I' ve heard.
我聽過這句了
Nothing beats a first...
什麼事都比不上初...
What are you doing?
你幹嘛？
Nothing. I was just getting some lint off for you.
沒什麼，幫你撿線頭
You were going for a feelski!
你偷襲我胸部
All right, I' m sorry, but this is like the 23rd time we've made out already...
對不起，但我們已經這樣23次了...
...and they're getting blue.
我快憋壞了
I know. I know.
我知道
I mean, I really don't know.
我是說，我不知道
For me, it still feels like the first time.
對我而言，這感覺還是第一次
Okay, let's average it out then.
那我們算平均值好了
It's the 23rd time for me and the first time for you.
這是我第23次，你第一次
- That's about our 12th time. - Yeah?
-那就算是我們的第12次 -是嗎？
Now, Hawaiian law clearly states after the 12th date...
夏威夷法律規定約會12次後...
...I' m entitled to unlimited boob access.
我有權任意襲胸
Why didn't I meet you one day before the accident?
我出事前一天能認識你就好了
You say that all the time.
你老愛說這句話
You want to meet a friend of mine?
要不要去見我一個朋友？
All right.
好了
Jocko, this is Lucy. Lucy, this is Jocko.
這是露西，這是肥仔
Wow! Thank you. Nice to meet you.
謝謝你，真是幸會
He is awesome! He is so smart.
他真棒！他好聰明
Check this out. Jocko, what does the teapot do when the water's ready?
你看著 肥仔，水壺燒好水會怎樣？
- Very good. - Can I ask him a question?
-很好 -我能問他問題嗎？
Go ahead.
問吧
Jocko...
肥仔...
...do you think that Henry and I are ready to take our relationship...
你想亨利和我...
...to the next level
可以有進一步的關係了嗎？
You sure about that?
你確定？
Do you think I should bring him into the other room...
你想我該帶他進房間...
...and take advantage of him?
讓他佔我便宜？
I saw that hand gesture.
我看到暗號了
- And I' m glad you did it. - Really?
-我很高興 -真的？
- Use that. - Oh, wow. Look!
-用那個 -你看！
- Yeah. - They're...
-是啊 -他們...
They're nodding in approval, I hope.
他們在點頭 希望是表示滿意
They like you. Let me get them out of there.
他們很喜歡你，我叫他們走開
Mary-Kate, Ashley, get a life. Thank you. Sorry.
哼哈雙豚，去別的地方吧
- Oh, they're very nice, though. - Yeah, so are you.
-他們很好心 -你也是
Let me get you down slow.
我慢慢的讓你躺下
- Thank you. - My pleasure.
-謝謝 -我的榮幸
All right, I just wrote this, so go easy on me.
我剛寫下這首歌，別太挑剔
The Hukilau was the place
地點就是小吃店
Where I first saw your face
我初次與你相遇
We liked each other right away
你我立即相傾心
But you didn't remember me The very next day
但你隔天就忘了我
Forgetful Lucy
善忘的露西
Has got a nice caboose-y
前凸後翹好身材
I used to trick you into pulling Your car over so we could chat
我曾騙你停車跟你搭訕
But my favorite time was when you Beat the shit out of Ula with a bat
但我最愛的時刻 卻是你海扁芭樂那一次
And we drove up to see Dr. Keats
還有我們去看醫生
And found out why Doug always Has to change his sheets
發現了道格的秘密
Forgetful Lucy
善忘的露西
Cracked her head like Gary Busey
腦袋天天重開機
But I still love her so
但我還是深愛她
And I'll never let her go
永遠不會離開她
Even if while I'm singing this song
就在我唱歌的當下
She's wishing I had Jocko the Walus' schlong
她還希望我跟胖仔一樣猛
Forgetful Lucy
善忘的露西
Her lips are so damn juicy
她的唇兒甜如蜜
How about another first kiss
再來一次初吻吧
Can't fall asleep.
睡不著
I'm not sleeping.
我沒睡
I'm just closing my eyes.
我只是閉個眼
Well, I' m gonna go downstairs then.
那我下樓去吧
No, no. I' m just resting.
不要，我只是在休息
Lucy.
露西
Yeah.
什麼事？
Will you marry me?
你願意嫁給我嗎？
- Of course. - Good.
-當然願意 -好
Don't forget about me.
別忘了我
Never.
永遠不會
Good morning.
早安
Oh, shit!
靠！
- Help! Help! - Whoa, whoa, whoa. Lucy.
-救命！ -哎，哎，哎，露西
Lucy! Lucy! Hey, hey, hey.
露西！等等
I know this is hard for you to understand...
我知道你現在很難明白...
...but we are actually seeing each other.
但我們其實是一對
We have been for a while now.
我們交往好一陣子了
Oh! Lucy! Lucy! Lucy!
露西！...
If I was lying, how would I know this?
我若說謊，怎會知道...
You're an art teacher and you go to the Hukilau every Sunday...
你是美術老師 你每週日都會去阿蘇小吃店...
...and you make waffle houses and you like Casablanca lilies.
你會蓋鬆餅屋，還喜歡百合花
- Stalker! - No, don't you remember me a little?
-跟蹤狂！ -你一點都不記得我了？
I may not be able to kick your ass, but my sister can.
也許我沒辦法開扁你 不過我老姐倒可以
Thanks, buddy.
謝了
Little Sammy Sosa's a bit shook up, but she'll be okay.
格鬥天女抓狂了，她沒事的
She's watching the tape as we speak.
她現在正在看帶子
How's my temporal lobe looking there, doc?
醫生，我的顳葉還好吧？
Don't worry. You're not gonna suffer any short-term memory loss.
別擔心，你不會喪失記憶的
But was your head shaped like an egg before she hit you?
你的頭原來就長的像鹹蛋嗎？
Don't make fun of Henry. It's not his fault it's shaped like that.
別鬧了，像鹹蛋又不是他的錯
Note the intense overreaction. That's the "roids" talking.
反應過度也是類固醇的副作用
- Doug, once again, off the juice. - It 's not juice.
-再說一次，別再吃禁藥了 -不是禁藥
It's a protein shake.
是高蛋白
Henry, the boys tell me you're setting sail for Alaska to study walruses.
他們說你要開船去阿拉斯加研究海象
- When does that adventure begin? - That actually began...
-這是何時開始的？ -10年前...
...ten years ago. That's when I started planning and building my boat.
我從那時開始存錢造船
All I know is, out of all mammals, they have the second-largest penis.
我只知道海象 他們有世上第二大的雞雞
I have the first.
第一大的是我
That's my joke.
那是我的笑話
Did you tell Lucy about this trip?
你跟露西提過這個旅行了？
Well...
這個嘛...
...actually, there's nothing to tell because I decided not to go.
其實沒什麼好說的 因為我決定不去了
I mean, Lucy needs me here.
露西需要我
I'm just worried about going away for a year...
我擔心離開一年之後...
...and ruining all the progress she's made.
會摧毀她一切的進展
I know you think I' m crazy...
我知道你認為我瘋了...
...but I think deep down inside...
但我覺得，在內心深處...
...she's starting to remember me. - No, Henry.
-她已經開始記得我了 -不
That's what you want to believe. It's what we all want to believe.
那是你自己想相信的 那也是我們都想相信的
But it's never gonna happen.
但是那不可能
Okay. I gotta go to work.
我得去上班了
Will you tell her I' II be back later to pick her up?
告訴她我會來接她
See you, guys. Don't tell anyone your sister beat me up.
回頭見，別跟你姐說她扁了我
He could go to the moon and back and Lucy would never even know he left.
那小子就算去一趟月球 露西也不會知道他離開過
Sometimes I wish my wife had Goldfield Syndrome.
真希望我老婆得了金氏症候群
That way she wouldn't remember when I called her mother...
那樣她就不記得我說過她老媽...
...a loud, obnoxious drunk with a face like J. Edgar Hoover's ass.
長得像得過天花加嘛瘋的如花
All right. There's your medicine, little fellow.
好，這是你的藥，小傢伙
Ula! Get back to cleaning the pool
芭樂！回去清理池子！
If that's one of your special brownies, don't let any of the dolphins eat that.
你的特製巧克力蛋糕 可別讓海豚吞下勝
How do you think I get them to double flip and play with white kids?
你以為我怎麼訓練海豚跳高 還教他們陪小鬼玩？
Okay, Willie, that's it.
好了，小威，就這樣
This time try to stay clean for more than a day.
這回試著保持乾淨吧
I made you a nice anchovy sundae.
我幫你準備了鯷魚聖代
Okay, enjoy that.
好好享受
Henry?
亨利？
- Hey! - How's your head?
-你好！ -你的頭沒事吧？
- Oh, it's fine. Don't worry. - Good.
-沒事，別擔心 -很好
What brings your royal cuteness out here?
怎麼有空大駕光臨？
I needed to see you.
我要見你
Okay. What you got there?
好吧，你手上拿著什麼？
It's my journal I write in it every night.
我的日記，我每晚都寫
- Oh, you don't like the video? - No, I love it.
-你不喜歡錄影帶？ -我喜歡
It's just sometimes when I watch it, I feel like I' m being told about my life...
只是有時我看帶子的時候 我總覺得是別人在說我的故事...
...from someone else. And when I read this...
而當我讀這本日記...
...it's like I' m telling myself.
則像是我自己告訴我自己
When did you start this up?
你何時開始寫的？
Right after you gave me the video.
就在你給我帶子之後
- Really? - I was so nervous to come here...
-真的？ -我心裡很緊張...
...and meet the guy that makes me fall in love with him every day.
要見讓我每天愛上他的男人
Well, you probably thought I couldn't live up to the hype.
你也許以為我會受不了這一切
No. I was nervous because...
不，我之所以緊張...
Because I came here to break up with you.
是為我是來跟你分手的
You had plans and a life...
在認識我之前...
...before you met me and now all you have time for...
你原本有個計劃、人生...
...is to make me fall in love with you.
現在你卻成天設法讓我愛上你
That's not all I do. I gave a penguin a bath today.
不只啦，我今天還幫企鵝洗澡
Which I' II have to do again tomorrow.
我明天還要幫他洗一次
Ilook at my dad and my brother's lives and I won't do that to you.
我看著我爸和我弟的生活 我不想讓你也那樣
What do you want me to do? Be some chapter in your scrapbook and go?
你要我在你生命裡 留下痕跡之後，翩然離去？
No.
不是
My plan is to erase you completely, so it's as if you never existed.
我打算將你完全抹去 就當你從未出現過
Why are you doing this?
你為什麼要這麼做？
Because you have to understand that there is no future with me.
因為你必須明白 跟我在一起沒有未來
Don't you want to have a career and marriage and children?
你難道不想要有一番事業 結婚生子？
I asked you to marry me. You said yes.
我昨晚向你求婚，你答應了
Kids? Yeah, I' d love to do it.
孩子？好，我想要有
But how is that going to work?
這怎麼可能呢？
I'm gonna wake up every morning with an enormous belly and no memory...
我每天醒來勝子逐漸變大 卻完全搞不清...
...of how it happened?
是怎麼回事？
I have to make a new journal that doesn't have you in it.
我得寫本新的、沒有你的日記
But before I do...
在那之前...
...I really want you to read what I wrote about you.
我要你先看過它
I will read about it tomorrow...
我明天再看...
...when you forget about all this breaking up stuff, okay?
等你忘了分手的事再說
I'm not going to forget it. I wrote it down. I won't let myself.
我不會忘的 我已經寫下來了，我不能忘
And I' m gonna do it whether you want me to or not.
不管你要不要，我都會這麼做
I'll be at my house.
我會待在家裡
Okay, type this one in there.
好，打下這段
Saturday, November 25th.
11月25日，週六
I drove out to Callahan Institute today and had a talk with Dr. Keats.
我今天去了療養院 跟醫生談了一下
There's one about me.
這裡有一段跟我有關
Reminder: He makes funny noises when I kiss his neck.
小小提醒 我親他脖子時，他會發出怪聲
I'm gonna miss that.
我會想念這個的
You sure you don't want me to put that in?
你真的不要我把這放進去？
- We can skip that one. - No, let me read it.
-這頁跳過 -讓我看看
We made love tonight! It didn't last long, but it was incredible.
我們今晚做愛了 雖然不夠久，但還是很棒
It's not all about how long you go. It 's... There was a connection, I thought.
久不久不重要... 重要的是感覺
Actually, let's just rip that out.
直接撕掉吧
Well, that's that.
結束了
Henry, wait!
亨利，等等！
Could I have one last first kiss?
能不能再給我一個初吻？
- I ain't gonna do this, Marlin. - You have to, Henry.
-我做不到 -你一定要做到
I'm gonna miss you, but I gotta get the hell off this island.
我會想你的，但我得走了
I'm sorry I can't take you...
抱歉我不能帶你一起走...
...but you've lived here so long you're too big of a pansy to defend yourself.
你在這裡住太久了 到野外根本搶不到母海象
I don't feel bad for you. I know you got a thing going on with Candace.
我不會覺得你很悲哀 我知道你跟阿珠有一腿
Candace and Bernice?
阿珠跟阿花？
Candace, Bernice and Rose?
阿珠、阿花、還有阿霞？
Yeah. I fell for one chick and I' m losing my mind. Good luck with that.
我愛上一個女人就頭暈腦脹了 祝你好運
Okay, baby.
好啦
Ilove you.
我愛你
Thanks, buddy. Remember to use a condom.
謝了，兄弟，記得戴保險套
Or in your case, a Hefty bag.
你的話，用超大號塑膠袋吧
Well...
各位...
Okay, you guys. Thanks for coming to say goodbye.
謝謝你們來送行
Be careful
保重
You make sure your father doesn't get eaten by a shark.
看好你阿爸，別讓鯊魚吞了他
Thank you, buddy. What does that mean again?
謝了，兄弟，那是什麼意思？
Bring me back a T-shirt.
帶件T恤回來給我
Oh, okay. You got it.
好吧，沒問題
Come here. All right. Love you guys.
過來，我愛你們
My shirt size is medium husky.
我的T恤尺寸是M
Hey! Kikikuloa!
死小孩！
No flippies off the dock! You could get hurt!
別亂跳水！會受傷的！
No! All right. Let the master show you how to get it done.
好吧，讓大師來跳給你們看
Now you kids go down there and find my nuts.
你們快幫我找鳥蛋吧
Sure you don't want to take Doug?
你真的不帶道格一起去？
Hey! What the heck are you guys doing here?
你們怎麼來了？
I spoke to the harbormaster and he said you were setting sail today...
我跟港務局長談過 他說你今天出航...
...so we thought we'd wish you bon voyage.
所以我們來祝你一路順風
This is from Nick and Sue. They send their best wishes.
這是大胖和阿蘇送的
That's very nice. Spam and Reese's. All right.
真好，火腿罐頭，好耶
Ilove Spam and Reese's. Can I have it?
我超愛吃火腿，可以給我嗎？
I guess.
可以吧
- Doug! - That's all right.
-道格！ -沒關係啦
- I' m sorry. - So...
-真抱歉 -那個...
...how's Lucy?
露西還好吧？
Actually, she's living at the institute.
她現在住療養院了
- When did that happen? - Three weeks ago.
-這是什麼時候的事？ -三周之前
Said she didn't want to be a burden to me and Doug anymore. I don't know.
她說她不想再拖累我們了
I couldn't talk her out of it. You know what?
我沒辦法說服她
She's doing really great up there.
她在那裡過的很好
She's teaching an art class and she gets to paint every day.
她在那裡還開班教劃劃
In fact, she's even singing again.
她甚至又開始唱歌了
Hey, look, I got a little gift for you too.
亨利，我也有個小禮物送你
It's just a little something from one sailor to another one.
水手送水手的禮物
You take care of yourself out there.
出門在外要小心
- I will. - Okay.
-我會的 -很好
Henry did not tell me about you.
亨利沒跟我提過你
Your fisherman muscles.
還有你的雄壯肌肉
Can I touch?
我能碰一下嗎？
Sure.
當然
Yes.
好耶
The Beach Boys?
海灘男孩？
How nice of him to give me a CD that will remind me...
這傢伙竟然送我一張CD 讓我想起...
...of all the wonderful times I shared with his daughter.
我跟她女兒的美好戀情
What an asshole!
真是個老混蛋！
Oh, why?
為什麼？
Why would you do this to me?
你為什麼這麼對我？
You sick bastard!
你這個死老頭！
Oh, my God.
我的媽呀
Is he trying to tell me something?
他是不是想告訴我什麼？
She only sings on days she meets you.
她只在遇見你的日子唱這首歌
She remembers me?
她記得我？
Holy shit!
哇靠！
She remembers me!
她記得我！
Julia, that looks great.
茱莉，你劃的很好
Excuse me. What am I doing?
借問一下，我在幹嘛？
You're painting a picture. And you're doing an excellent job.
你在劃劃，你劃的很好
Oh.
這樣喔
Holy crap! I suck.
媽啦，我真爛
Hey, hey, hey.
等等
- Can we help you, sir? - Yes. I have an appointment.
-先生，有事嗎？ -我有預約
- What's your name? - My name?
-你的名字是？ -我的名字？
Dude, he forgot his name. I feel bad for him.
他忘了啦，真可憐
Just go on up. And good luck with that memory problem.
上去吧，祝你記憶能恢復
Yeah. Thank you.
謝謝
What?
幹嘛？
Lucy!
露西！
- Hi, I' m Tom. - Hey, I met you before. I' m Henry.
-你好，我是湯姆 -我們見過，我是亨利
Maybe you can help me. I'm looking for Lucy Whitmore.
我找惠露西
Any idea where I can find her?
你知道她在哪裡嗎？
Hi, I' m Tom.
你好，我是湯姆
Oh. Thanks anyways.
真多謝了
Lucy!
露西！
Lucy Whitmore...
惠露西...
...can I ask you a question?
我能問你一個問題嗎？
Do you have any idea who I am?
你知道我是誰嗎？
- No. - No?
-不知道 -不知道？
That sucks.
真糟糕
- What's your name? - I' m Henry.
-你叫什麼名字？ -我叫亨利
Henry.
亨利
I want to show you something. Will you come with me?
跟我來，我有東西讓你看
Well, yeah.
好
Hey. Do you know who that guy is?
你知道那傢伙是誰嗎？
Dude, I don't even know who I am.
我連我是誰都不知道了
Oh, well, you're Pablo Picasso.
你是畢加索
- Really? - No. Not really.
-真的？ -不是真的
This is my studio.
這是我的工作室
I don't know who you are, Henry...
我不知道你是誰，亨利...
...but I dream about you almost every night.
但我幾乎每晚都夢見你
Why?
為什麼？
What would you say if I told you that notebook you read every day...
要是我告訴你 你每天都看的那本日記...
...used to have a lot of stuff about me in it?
曾經記錄著很多我的事呢？
I would say that that makes a lot of sense.
我會說那很有可能
You erased me from your memories...
你把我從你記憶裡抹去...
...because you thought you were holding me back from having...
因為你以為你拖累了我...
...a full and happy life.
害我無法擁有快樂的人生
But you made a mistake.
但是你錯了
Being with you is the only way I could have a full and happy life.
我只有跟你在一起才會快樂
You're the girl of my dreams...
你是我最完美的伴侶...
...and apparently I' m the man of yours.
而我顯然也是你的完美伴侶
Henry.
亨利
It's nice to meet you.
真高興認識你
Lucy, it's nice to meet you too.
露西，我也一樣
Hi, I' m Tom.
你好，我是湯姆
Henry, Lucy. Nice to meet you, Tom.
亨利、露西，幸會，湯姆
Now why don't you come back in ten seconds so we can meet again?
十秒後再來，我們再相識一次
Do you, Honah Lee, take this woman to be your lawfully wedded wife...
亨利，你是否願意...
...to have and to hold from this day forh...
娶這位女子為妻...
...as long as you both shall live?
從今起彼此相互扶持 直到永遠？
- I do. - Really?
-我願意 -真的？
Even though in, like, 10, 15 years...
縱使經過10到15年後...
...she could possibly let herself go and then, like...
她可能會變成超丑肥豬母...
...sex could be, like, nauseating for you?
讓你倒盡胃口不想上床？
What are you, nuts? Your wife's right over there.
你瘋啦？你老婆在場耶
I'm just kidding, Muumuu!
我開玩笑的啦，如花
I now pronounce you man and wife.
我宣佈你們結為夫妻
Mazel tov!
恭喜！
It's very cold, so when you're ready...
外面很冷，上來要加衣服...
...put on a jacket and come have breakfast with me. Love you.
跟我一起吃早餐吧，我愛你
Hey, hey! Good morning, Mrs. Roth. Would you like to meet your daughter?
早安，羅太太 見過你女兒吧？
Go say hello to Mommy.
跟媽咪打招呼
Hi, Mommy.
媽咪
That's right.
很好
Good morning.
早安
Oh, my goodness!
老天爺！
- Grandpa's here. - Hi, Dad.
-爺爺在這裡 -阿爸